ybs.co.uk 2017-11-18

# Privacy and Cookies - Yorkshire Building Society

By using this site you are consenting to the use of cookies. Find out more about cookies and why we use them

[x close] 

_BANK RATE CHANGE_  
On 2 November 2017, the Bank of England announced that the Bank Base Rate would increase with immediate effective from 0.25% to 0.50%.

Find out more

  * 
  * Mortgages
  * Savings
  * Insurance
  * Life Planning
  * Help & Support

You are here: Home /  Privacy and Cookies

###  The privacy and security of your personal information is very important to us. We will not disclose it to anyone except with your consent or if the law, public duty or our legitimate interests require us to. 

##  How we use your personal information 

When you register an enquiry or complete an application you will be agreeing to the use of your personal information.

We will use your personal information, together with other information available including sensitive information, as appropriate, to process your enquiry, set up and administer the account and services you have with us, contact you where necessary, for fraud prevention and detection, legal and regulatory compliance, marketing and market research and general business purposes.

  1. ####  Our relationships with other companies

If we offer you products or services from other companies (and you take these products you will be entering into a contract with the company concerned) we will share relevant information with them to obtain a quote and administer the service provided.

We are careful to choose reputable companies governed by regulatory bodies.

All relationships with third parties are controlled by a contract that safeguards the security and confidentiality of your information.

  2. ####  Customer Services

If you subscribe to one of our special customer services e.g. our Savings Pledges—to be kept informed of new savings accounts by email, we will use these details for this service until you unsubscribe from this service and these details will be removed. These services are not linked to and do not affect the marketing permissions and other details you have registered with us. 
  3. ####  Marketing

Unless you have indicated that you do not want to be contacted for marketing, we will use any details we have obtained, at any time, to communicate with you and will only do so by the methods you have chosen. We do not market to children.
  4. ####  Share Plans

If you are a member of an employee share scheme administered by us we 
    1. will use information provided by your employer to check your eligibility
    2. may disclose information about your scheme participation to your employer for the purpose of administering the account
    3. notify you of additional products and services that may be of interest to you unless our contract with your employer prohibits us from doing so or you have told us that you do not want us to do this.
  5. ####  Help to Buy: ISA Scheme

If a ISA account is registered as a Help to Buy: ISA Scheme we will share personal information and details with HM Treasury, UKAR the Administrator of the scheme and any appointed contractors and third parties to enable them to 
    1. administer the scheme, including confirmation of eligibility and paying bonuses
    2. carry out data reporting, compliance, investigations, audit and fraud prevention work necessary to run the scheme.
    3. compile management statistical information about the performance of the scheme

  6. ####  Email

You should note that ordinary email is not secure. Please do not send us any confidential information via email. Similarly, we will not use email to send confidential information about your accounts to you unless you specifically request, and agree to, this. For your own protection, please do not include confidential or other personal information in any unprotected e-mails you send to us
  7. ####  Site monitoring

We use technical methods (called "cookies") to identify what stage in an application process you are at, improve your experience by making it quicker and easier for you to use the site, identify how effective our advertising is and provide you with information in the future we believe is relevant to you. No personal information is captured unless you proceed with an application at which point details of where your enquiry originated will be linked to your customer record. You can block or delete cookies from this site in your browser settings. To find out how to delete cookies visit [www.aboutcookies.org.](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) By doing this your experience may be affected and parts of this site may not work. By continuing with an enquiry/application you will be consenting to the use of cookies as explained.
  8. ####  Communicating with others

All communications with us may be monitored/recorded to improve the quality of our service, staff training and for your protection and security.
  9. ####  Links to other sites

This Privacy Policy only covers you while you are on our site. Once you click on a link to another website, the Policy no longer applies.
  10. [Applying for a job](http://www.ybs.jobs/apply/your-personal-information/)

For full details see our leaflet How we use your personal information (200 KB) that also provides detailed information about Business Relationships, Sources and sensitive information.

To view some of the document you will need to have Adobe Acrobat reader installed. If you have not already got this and would like to download it, visit the [Adobe web site.](http://www.adobe.com/)

##  Data Protection Act - Your Rights 

You have the right to have any inaccuracies corrected, to object to direct marketing at any time and a right of access to your personal records held by us, subject to the payment of a fee.

Complete a Submit Access Request Form (96 KB)

###  Full details of your rights and the Data Protection Act

Our leaflet Your rights and the Data Protection Act (254 KB) has full details about all your rights under the Data Protection Act and how to invoke them. It also includes information about our legal obligations to you, and the Credit Reference and Fraud Prevention Agencies we use along with other useful information.

To view the document you will need to have Adobe Acrobat reader installed. If you have not already got this and would like to download it, visit the [Adobe web site.](http://www.adobe.com/)

##  Cookies - Site monitoring 

We use technical methods (called "cookies") on this website. A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that allows us to:

  * Identify what stage in an application process you are at.
  * Improve your experience by making it quicker and easier for you to use the site. 
  * Identify how effective our advertising is and provide you with information in the future we believe is relevant to you. 

Temporary or session cookies are also needed for you to log in and to manage your savings and mortgage accounts.

No personal information is captured unless you proceed with an application at which point details of where your enquiry originated may be linked to your customer record. By continuing with an enquiry/ application you will be consenting to the use of cookies as explained.

If you have come to this site by clicking on a Yorkshire Building Society advertisement on another website you may have had a cookie placed on your PC either by Yorkshire Building Society or the website provider. This allows us and/or them to analyse the effectiveness of our online advertising. See **Managing / Blocking cookies** for information about deleting these cookies.

####  Important Information

  * By using our website, including making an enquiry/application or logging in, you are consenting to the use of cookies as explained above.
  * For more information about cookies visit [www.allaboutcookies.org.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/)

###  Managing/Blocking cookies

You can manage cookies from this site, including blocking or deleting them, by changing the settings in the browser you use, e.g. Internet Explorer, Mozilla Firefox, Google Chrome, etc.

Find out how you can do this by visiting [www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/.](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies/)

#### Please note

  * By doing this your experience may be affected and parts of the site may not work.

##  Queries 

Contact us if you have any queries about the privacy of this site. 

###  Or, write to us

**Customer Relations Department** Yorkshire Building Society Yorkshire House Yorkshire Drive Bradford West Yorkshire BD5 8LJ

##  Get in touch 

###  Call us

  * 8am - 8pm: Mon to Fri
  * 9am - 1pm: Sat

**Online security**  
Report an online security issue using our form

###  Report a lost/stolen card

Call our helpline 24 hours a day, 7 days a week

Alternatively you can visit your local branch or report it online
